<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zfs on tactical-documentation</title>
    <link>https://tactical-documentation.github.io/tags/zfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zfs on tactical-documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tactical-documentation.github.io/tags/zfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting Proxmox VE 6: ZFS, LUKS, systemd-boot and Dropbear</title>
      <link>https://tactical-documentation.github.io/post/proxmoxve6-zfs-luks-systemdboot-dropbear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactical-documentation.github.io/post/proxmoxve6-zfs-luks-systemdboot-dropbear/</guid>
      <description>This describes how to set up a fully encrypted Proxmox VE 6 host with ZFS root and unlocking it remotely using the dropbear ssh server. Also it describes how you can do that, while keeping systemd-boot and thus also the pve tooling intactI&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the pve tooling still works if you replace systemd-boot with grub, which seems to be the common solution to setting up this kind of setup,maybe it does .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof of Concept: Adding Boot Environments to Proxmox VE 6</title>
      <link>https://tactical-documentation.github.io/post/poc-proxmox-and-boot-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactical-documentation.github.io/post/poc-proxmox-and-boot-environments/</guid>
      <description>Dear Reader, this time I would like to invite you onto a small journey: To boldly go where no man has gone beforeAlright, that&amp;rsquo;s not true, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s the first time someone documents this kind of thing in the context of Proxmox . We&amp;rsquo;re about to embark on a journey to make your Proxmox host quite literally immortal. Also since what we are essentially doing here is only a Proof of concept, you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use it in production, but as it&amp;rsquo;s really amazing, so you might want to try it out in a test environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a Boot Environment Manager for Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://tactical-documentation.github.io/post/a-boot-environment-manager-for-proxmox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactical-documentation.github.io/post/a-boot-environment-manager-for-proxmox/</guid>
      <description>This post introduces a fork of the FreeBSD beadm utility which can be used to manage Boot Environments on Proxmox ZFS Installations.
In this Post I will showcase how to use the beadm Boot Environment manager in Proxmox. After the showcase there are some notes on what I did to make beadm run on Linux in general and finally a part about what has been changed in order to make beadm work with Proxmox specifically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>